<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Measurements</string>
    <string name="phenomena_and_illusions">Phenomena and Illusions</string>
    <string name="phenomena_and_illusions_title">Phenomena and Illusions</string>
    <string name="phenomena_and_illusions_content">
        <br/>
        - Physics is the scientific study of how matter and energy interact.
        <br/>
        <br/>
        - This interaction can produce the colors of the rainbow in a shower
        <br/>
        <br/>
        - At a greater distance, the interaction of matter and energy in the Sun produces
        light and heat. In our eyes the light energy is converted into electrical energy,
        which passes to our brain and allows us to see objects in front of us.
    </string>
    <string name="sub1_content">
        <br/>
        - A rainbow is a meteorological phenomenon that appears as a multicolored arc that
        forms with sunlight.
    </string>
    <string name="measuring_length_mass_and_time">measuring_length_mass_and_time</string>
    <string name="title_settings_activity">SettingsActivity</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="fun_fact_title">Fun facts</string>
    <string name="fun_fact_content">
        Fun fact 1:
        <br/><i>Horsepower</i> is a well-known unit of measurement, but do you know that there is another
        unit of measurement called "donkey power"? It is defined as 250 watts, which is about a third
        of a horsepower.

        <br/><br/>Fun fact 2:
        <br/>You probably know that there is a small amount of radiation in a banana due to the presence
        of a natural isotope of potassium. There is actually an informal term for the amount which
        is called <i>banana equivalent dose</i> (BED). It was intended to be a general educational example
        to compare a dose of radioactivity to the dose one is exposed to by eating an average-sized
        banana. To be slightly technical, one BED is equivalent to 0.1 microsieverts.

        <br /><br />Fun fact 3:
        <br />A British YouTuber Tom Scott defines the term <i>onosecond</i>, in one of his video titled:
        "The Worst Typo I Ever Made", as the second after one makes a terrible mistake, where
        everything you can do is to say: "Oh no".

        <br/><br/>Fun fact 4:
        <br/>One of the most ridiculous name of a unit of measurement is <i>pirate-ninja</i>. A
        pirate-ninja is defined as a kilowatt-hour per Martian day or sol. It is equivalent to
        approximately 40.55 watts.

        <br/><br/>Fun fact 5:
        <br/>Inspired by Mickey Mouse created by Walt Disney, one <i>Mickey</i> is the smallest resolvable unit of
        distance by a given computer mouse pointing device. Mouse motion is reported in horizontal
        and vertical mickeys. Device sensitivity is usually specified in mickeys per inch. Typical
        resolution is 16 mickeys per millimeter. Available resolutions are up to 600 mickeys per
        millimeter.

        <br/><br/>Fun fact 6:
        <br/>A <i>fortnight</i> is defined as 14 days, but do you know that fortnight is part of a system
        called the FFF system? The full name of FFF system is furlong-firkin-fortnight system. It is
        based on unusual or impractical measurements. <i>Furlong</i> is the unit of length (1 furlong = 201.168m),
        <i>firkin</i> is the unit of mass (1 firkin = 40.8233133kg), and <i>fortnight</i> is the unit of time
        (1 fortnight = 14 days). Despite being old and impractical, Myanmar still uses furlong in
        conjunction with miles to indicate distances on highway signs. Also, the terms was originated
        in England in the late 13th or early 14th century, therefore during the 16th century, before
        the SI units and the imperial units (18th century), furlong is used on horse racing in England
        and they are still using it today.

        <br/><br/>Fun Fact 7:
        <br/>Heart beat has an average of 80 beats per minute, that is 4,800 times per hour and 115,200
        times per day. Assume you live to be 80 years old, your heart would have beaten approximately
        3,363,840,000 times. Every beat pumps around 70 ml of blood, that means 5.6 litres per minute,
        336 litres per hour, 8064 litres per day, and assume you live to 80 years old, that is
        235,468,800 litres of blood.

        <br/><br/>Fun Fact 8:
        <br/>This one may be a little not safe for work (NSFW). But to correctly measure a penis,
        urologists recommends a measurement method called Bone Pressed Flaccid Length (BPFL).
        Basically, the standard by which you should use for comparison against other bone-pressed size
        studies is called Bone-Pressed Measurement (BP) in which you push a ruler or measuring instrument
        into the fat or skin all the way to the pubic bone. On the other hand, Non-Bone-Pressed
        Measurement (NBP) is the visible length of the penis which is NOT good for statistical comparison
        as it fluctuates depending on the body fat level and potentially other factors. An example
        for this would be a person with the body fat of 20% could have a possible NBP gain of 1.397 cm.

        <br/><br/>Fun Fact 9:
        <br/>To be honest, this is not so fun of a fact. The longest human neck can extend to 19.7 cm,
        this record belong to women in the Padaung/Kayan tribe in the highlands of northwestern Thailand
        and southeastern Myanmar. As a cultural practice, the tribe uses heavy brass rings on the necks
        of female from the age 5 to 9 and add more as they age. The rings increases the length of neck by
        pressing down on the ribcage and lower jaw. Over time the weight of the rings distorts the
        musculature of the shoulders, bends the collarbone and ribcage, and compresses the lower jaw.
        This creates the impression that the neck has been lengthened. Although through X-ray,
        we can see that the vertebrae that form the cervical spine are actually unchanged. And this
        practice actually causes respiratory and cardiovascular problems, and distorted dental development,
        causing a significant reduction of life expectancy of the women of the tribe.

        <br/><br/>Fun Fact 10:
        <br/>According to Dr. Maggie Aderin-Pocock who ran computer simulations on the distance between
        the Moon and Earth, the Moon was much closer to the Earth, which was only 22,500 km away comparing
        to today which furthest apart (Apogee) is more than 400,000 km away. As of right now, the Moon
        continues to spin away from the Earth at the rate pf 3.78 km per year. Without the Moon, the
        Earth could slow down enough to become unstable. However, that would take billions of years
        and may never even happen at all.

        <br/><br/>Fun Fact 11:
        <br/>A single 200 ml glass of dairy milk uses up around 120 litres of water. The water is used
        mostly for cows and to grow their food. Meanwhile, almond milk takes nearly 70 litres of water
        per glass, and most of it is used to grow almond trees. Soy and oat milk only take 5 - 10
        litres of water per glass.

        <br/><br/>Fun Fact 12:
        <br/>Human shed about 600,000 particles of skin every hour, which works out to be about 0.68
        kg of skin per year,or a total of 54.4 kg assuming you reach the age of 80.

        <br/><br/>Fun Fact 13:
        <br/>If you have the mean to do it, the longest possible uninterrupted walk without boat or
        air journey on Earth is 22,387 km long from Cape Town, South Africa to Magadan, Russia and vice
        versa. According to Google Map, it takes 4,492 hours or 187 days of non-stop walking to get
        there.
    </string>

</resources>